vzw.com 2004-12-29

# Verizon Wireless Privacy Statement

Effective Date: This policy was last updated on 06/14/2004.

Verizon Wireless strives to maintain high standards for the protection of privacy over the Internet. The purpose of this statement is to explain to our visitors the type of information Verizon Wireless obtains about visitors to our websites, how we gather it, how we use it, how long we retain it, and how visitors can restrict the use or disclosure of personally identifiable information.

### Verizon Wireless as a licensee of the TRUSTe privacy program

The TRUSTe seal confirms that Verizon Wireless is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first [contact us](http://www.verizonwireless.com/b2c/vzwfly?go=/ContactUsControllerServlet&item=_FAQ_TOPIC&navigationLinkOptions=GLOBAL_HEADER). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the website to resolve your concerns.

### Information we collect

The personal information Verizon Wireless obtains about individual visitors to our websites is information the visitor supplies voluntarily. This means that you can visit our websites without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself. To gauge the effectiveness of our websites, we do collect some generic information about our visitors. Our web servers automatically recognize a visitor's domain name (such as .com, .edu, etc.), the point of entry from which a visitor enters our site including web pages, User Guide CDs or banner ads, which pages a visitor visits on our site, and how much time a visitor spends on each page. This information is not linked to any personally identifiable information about the visitor. We or our contractors use web beacons (i.e., "cookies") to track use of our sites and to track what sites users came from, but do not collect personally identifiable information via these web beacons. We aggregate this information and use it to evaluate and improve our websites. We do not track user activity on sites outside of Verizon Wireless. 

Verizon Wireless may collect personally identifiable information (such as name, email address, postal address) and/or third party personally identifiable information through this website. In some situations, such as when you order a product or service online or register for online billing, Verizon Wireless will collect billing information, such as your credit card number and billing address, and we may share this information with our third parties contractors (such as your credit card company solely for the purpose of processing the transaction you have requested). You may choose to provide individual information to Verizon Wireless in a number of ways through our websites such as by:

  * Ordering a product or service from us; 
  * Sending us email; 
  * Registering to receive news, public policy updates, or information about our products or services; 
  * Applying for a job or a grant; or 
  * Entering a contest. 

When visitors supply information about themselves for a specific purpose, Verizon Wireless uses the information for that purpose (such as to provide the information the visitor has requested or to consider a visitor for a particular job). When visitors use our websites to order products or services, or to request information about them, we may use the individual information as we would use the same information obtained offline - for example, to evaluate your service needs and contact you regarding additional services you may find useful. You have the right to choose not to receive this information by notifying us of your preference.

When a user wants to set up an account with Verizon Wireless, in order to determine the user's credit worthiness, we use their name, date of birth, and social security number to request a credit report from a credit-reporting agency. Once we determine a user's credit-worthiness, this document is destroyed.

We do not sell individual information obtained online about our visitors. And, we will not disclose the individual information provided to us online to anyone outside of Verizon Wireless or our contractors unless you specifically authorize it (by purchasing a product or service using a credit card, for example, you authorize us to provide information regarding the purchase to your credit card company), it is required by law, or disclosure is necessary to protect the safety of customers, employees or property. If you provide individual information to us in the context of an event Verizon Wireless sponsors with another company, such as a contest, or if you register on a co-sponsored site or feature, you may also be providing the information to the co-sponsor. In those circumstances, the co-sponsor's privacy policy will control, so review their information carefully. Verizon Wireless from time to time uses third party contractors to perform services such as website management, site design, site hosting and special promotions but does not use user information for other purposes beyond providing specific services on Verizon Wireless website.

### Email

Verizon Wireless does not send unsolicited "junk" email (spam). We may use email to communicate with our customers, to respond to visitors' emails, to confirm orders placed online, and to send information that a visitor has requested. If you receive an unwanted email from us, you can simply reply to ask not to receive future emails.

Verizon Wireless provides an unsubscribe function in its email campaigns in order for subscribers to opt out of further email communications from us.

### Use of cookies

Verizon Wireless websites also use "cookies", which may be sent by contractors that we use to track how our websites are used. They allow us to serve you better. When you use our sites, we or our contractors send information, a cookie, to your computer and it is stored there. When you return to our sites, your computer sends the cookie back to us or our contractor. This allows our server to recognize your computer and any settings you created on our sites. It restores those settings so you don't have to enter the same information every time you visit. For example, if you entered your zip code on a visit to our site, when you return you will see information for that zip code without typing it in again. It also allows us to track non-personally identifiable information about how our websites are used and how to improve them. The fact that our server recognizes your computer when it retrieves the cookies does not mean that Verizon Wireless is actually acquiring information about you. You can set your browser to delete cookies or to tell you before you accept one. Look in your browser's Options or Preferences menu.

### Security

Verizon Wireless uses Secure Socket Layer technology with encryption for the transmission of sensitive data such as credit card information and Social Security Number.

Verizon Wireless is committed to safeguarding customer privacy on all our websites. We require our employees to protect the privacy of information about our customers and expect our partners and suppliers to do so as well. You can feel confident that your individual information will be protected when you access your account or order products or services from our websites. We employ security measures to safeguard your transactions with us.

### Compliance with laws

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our websites.

### Links to other websites

The Verizon Wireless websites contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by other sites. To improve the services it can offer you, Verizon Wireless may opt to expand its capabilities for obtaining information about users in the future. Verizon Wireless will update this privacy statement continually to ensure that you are aware of developments in this area.

### Updating your information

Users may access, correct, and update information they have provided to Verizon Wireless by visiting our websites and utilize our Customer Care application. The Contact Us area of the site contains email links by which users can send in information updates.

### Notice of changes

Verizon Wireless will provide 30 days notice on our web site of any material changes to the privacy statement and in the use of personally identifiable information.

### Contacting us

For inquiries regarding our privacy statement, contact us. Or send your comments to:

Content Manager, S4162  
Verizon Wireless  
30 Independence Boulevard  
Warren, NJ 07059

Verizon Wireless endorses the Verizon Communications, Inc. Privacy Statement. They state our commitment to and define our policy on safeguarding customer privacy on their website. Read the [Verizon Communications Privacy Policy](http://www22.verizon.com/privacy/?loc=HH "Verizon Communications Privacy Policy").
